Flynn Rider: This is the
story of how I died...
and went to heaven! (chuckles)
Okay, so the Kingdom of Corona,
to be exact,
but hey, let's not get hung up
on semantics.
Once upon a time,
a single drop of sunlight
fell from the heavens...
You know what?
I'm just gonna give you
the rapid-fire shorthand here.
The sundrop created a golden
flower with healing powers,
creepy, old, Mother Gothel sang a song
to said flower to regain her youth.
Yada, yada, yada, the queen
got sick, flower healed queen,
queen gave birth to Rapunzel, who was born
with the flower's magical healing powers,
and everything was all flying
lanterns and cheering subjects,
until... Gothel stole the princess
and kept her locked in a tower
for 18 long years.
Then the princess was rescued
by a dashing, steely-eyed,
suave, smoldering,
devilishly charming rogue.
Now, some people might
have called him a thief,
but I always preferred the term
"misunderstood good guy."
You see, it wasn't always easy
for young Eugene.
Raised as an orphan
on the rough streets of...
Rapunzel: Hey, Eugene. Focus?
Eugene: Huh? Oh, right. Sorry.
So, the beautiful
young maiden, that's you,
and the handsome rogue,
that's me, made a deal.
We followed some lanterns,
I saved you from Gothel,
you saved me from... death,
and then you got arguably the world's
most overly dramatic haircut.
- And then...
- Rapunzel: And then,
I was reunited with my long-lost family.
But that is where our new story began.
Six months had passed,
I was loving life
inside the Kingdom of Corona,
and my coronation
to officially become princess
had finally come.
Eugene: We all had a few
surprises that day.
- Didn't we, sunshine?
- (Pascal squeaks)
Eugene: Laugh it up, frog.
Rapunzel: Now, I know
what you're all thinking.
Yes, Eugene and I did get married.
But make no mistake,
getting to the wedding day
and our happily ever after
would be the biggest adventure
we would ever face.
Eugene: Oh, that's good.
They're gaining on us.
There's more of them!
Good. It'll keep things interesting.
Man, these guys are persistent.
So am I. I'll meet you at the wall.
Sounds like a challenge.
Think you can keep up?
Oh, it's not me you have to worry about.
Uh-oh.
They're your problem now.
Oh, great.
Okay, Max, follow my lead...
Oh, log, log, log!
Ooh, good thing
the ground broke his fall.
- (squeaks) Huh?
- Whoa, bunny crossing!
Careful Fidela, watch out,
watch out. Cute little bunnies.
- (horse grunts)
- (bunnies squeak)
You're not getting away this time!
- Rapunzel: Hiya!
- (whinnies)
Sorry.
We're almost there.
Oh, come on!
Rapunzel: Whoo-hoo!
(whickers)
- (groans)
- (grunts)
- Looking good, Cap.
- (whinnies)
(whickers) Huh?
(sighs) Pascal, look at that view.
(sighs)
Haha!
Okay, okay, I know what you're thinking.
Now, it may have seemed like you won,
but you gotta take
into account that my hair
is actually longer than yours now,
so we gotta factor in wind resistance.
Hmm. Wow.
Have you ever seen
anything so beautiful?
Yes. Yes, I have.
Captain: The game's over, Your Highness.
The welcoming ceremony
is about to begin.
Well, I think we showed
those guards who's boss.
Now, what do you say we go
make you an official princess?
Oh, is that today?
Haha, very funny.
Now come on, we better get
you back to the castle.
Ooh, maybe I can squeeze in
a royal massage.
Before my daily trim, of course.
(squeaks)
I know, Pascal.
We'll get out there soon.
Ha. Race you back to the castle.
(sighs)
Rapunzel: ♪ This is life
after happily ever after ♪
♪ And it's all just as sweet
as the stories say ♪
♪ I feel wild, free,
as light as can be ♪
♪ And ready to explore ♪
♪ With nothing at all
standing in my way ♪
♪ True, there are certain
customs I have to follow ♪
Curtsy.
♪ Several small obligations
I can't avoid ♪
Princess, the time.
♪ A few rules, too...
well, more than a few ♪
♪ Commitments by the score ♪
♪ Aside from all that,
though, I'm overjoyed ♪
This way, Princess.
♪ And sure there are corsets
and buckles and bows ♪
♪ Plus all those names to recall ♪
- Jane? Right.
- Ethel.
♪ Still I can hardly
complain, I suppose ♪
♪ This is happily
ever after, after all ♪
That's enough. I'll take it from here.
How you holding up?
Busy.
But busy is good.
I'm glad you think so, Raps,
'cause this welcoming ceremony
is just the beginning.
Tomorrow's the festival,
followed by the royal banquet,
and that's all before the
actual coronation on Sunday.
Oh, come on, really?
Look, Rapunzel, I know this
princess thing is new to you,
but you've got to at least
try to act the part.
Trust me, Cassandra,
I know how important this is to my dad.
As you've requested, Your Majesty,
we've doubled security on both
the main gates and the south towers.
Good. We have guests
from all over the world.
I want them to know that they are safe.
Everything for my little girl's
coronation weekend
must be absolutely perfect.
Hi, Dad.
♪ And now that at last
you are here in my arms ♪
♪ I won't permit you to fall ♪
♪ I must protect you ♪
♪ From all the world's harms ♪
♪ We'll live happily
ever after, after all ♪
Now, as princess, you are not only
representing yourself and the family,
but all of Corona.
Don't worry, Dad. I won't let you down.
But while we're on the whole
princess, coronation thingy,
I mean, all these royal
activities are great,
but do you think I might be able
to catch a little downtime soon?
I know this is all new,
but you'll adjust.
After all, your friend seems
to be getting on just fine.
Ooh-hoo-hoo, Helmut, my man,
this hat ties the whole outfit together.
Now, I know what you're all thinking.
"Why is Eugene in such
a good mood today?
"I mean, what gives?"
♪ Now that we're living splendorly ♪
♪ Our dreams fulfilled extendedly ♪
♪ Why leave things open-endedly ♪
♪ For Rapunzel and moi? ♪
♪ Tonight I'll hand this rose to her ♪
♪ Kneel down and then propose to her ♪
♪ And give this ring I chose to her ♪
Nice.
♪ Life's gonna be
like strawberry sherbet ♪
♪ Once she is Mrs. Eugene Fitzherbert ♪
Okay, not great, but how about this?
♪ Once she is Princess
Eugene Fitzherbert ♪
And what better day to propose to a
princess than at her coronation?
Rapunzel and Eugene: ♪ This is
life after happily ever after ♪
♪ And our story has
finally reached its end ♪
- ♪ Settling down here ♪
- ♪ Year upon year ♪
♪ Contented and secure ♪
♪ With dozens of duties
we'll have to tend ♪
Both: ♪ And now that we've
gotten the dream that we chose ♪
♪ Now that we're in for the haul ♪
♪ Now our adventures
can come to a close ♪
♪ Living happily ever after, after all ♪
Rapunzel: ♪ Now that I've
gotten the dream that I chose ♪
♪ Why does my world feel so small? ♪
♪ If this is it ♪
♪ And it is, I suppose ♪
♪ Is this happily
ever after, after all? ♪
Okay, no pressure.
Just introducing myself
to the most important
people in the world.
Representing my mom, dad,
and the entire kingdom.
We got this.
(rat squeaking)
Lady Caine, what is it?
Time to pay our respects
to our beloved royals.
(fanfare playing)
We're good at making
people feel welcome.
This is completely doable... ish.
(clears throat)
Your Highness, I present
Dame Elizabeth Van Hoskins of Rochester.
(grunting)
Get in here!
So nice to meet you.
(squeaks)
Um, perhaps you should refrain
from the bear hugs, sweetheart.
Oh, no bear hugs. Gotcha. Sorry.
I present Lieutenant Commander
General James Rutherford-Carver III.
Phew. That's kind of a mouthful.
Is it okay if I call you Jimmy?
I'd prefer you didn't.
Well, um...
Welcome all the same then.
MC: I present the Duchess of Quintonia.
Wow, can I just say, I love your hair.
I used to have
really long hair too, but...
This is a handwoven coiffure
weft from the finest silk
and Vacuna fabrics.
It designates high social status.
You think you'd know that.
Uh, still. Nice to meet you.
Sadly not nice enough
to wear shoes, I'm afraid.
(laughs)
Really.
(huffs)
(whispers) Sorry.
So, I think we learned
something very valuable today.
There's a time and place for bear hugs.
(both chuckle)
Hey, are you okay?
Yeah, great. Why wouldn't I be?
(sighs) It's just...
Eugene, is all this everything
you dreamed it would be?
Rapunzel, you are my dream.
So as long as you're with me,
that answer's always gonna be yes.
Why? Don't you feel the same way?
No... Ye-Yes!
I mean, of course I do!
I love you with all my heart, Eugene.
Look, I know this has got be weird.
No one's expecting you
to take it all in overnight.
But believe me, I've been
all around the world
and it doesn't get any better than this.
This castle, our friends,
your family, each other.
What else could you possibly want?
Nothing.
Time to go!
(coughs)
(scoffs) How's
that water feeling, Fitzherbert?
(panting) Dark and icy.
Just like you.
(chuckles) Come on, Rapunzel,
it's time to head in.
You don't want to be
exhausted for tomorrow.
Right! My morning off!
Sorry!
Man, she scares me.
(trumpet playing fanfare)
The princess, Rapunzel,
will spend her day about town!
- (grunts)
- (squeaks)
(grunts)
Oh!
(grunting)
(sniffs)
Let me guess.
Big day on the town
wasn't all you hoped it'd be?
(sighs) It was... interesting.
(squeaks, sputters)
Uh huh, I bet.
I just wish my dad would let me
get out and see the real world.
You know, if you really wanted,
I could get you in and out of here
before anyone even knew
that we were gone.
(squeaks)
Uh, you mean sneak me out?
Exactly.
What you do when no one's
looking is your business.
(knock on door)
Woman: The royal banquet is ready
to receive the princess now.
Cheer up, Raps.
Hey, maybe your dad got someone
to chew your food for you.
(boy laughs)
I'm in charge of the seating charts.
One of the perks of the job.
(giggling)
I don't understand why
you are so upset, sweetheart.
I said you could do whatever you wanted.
That's exactly what you did.
Hmm, you didn't say anything
about a battalion tagging along.
Why would I need to?
You're royalty,
making a public appearance.
- But, Dad...
- (Eugene clears throat)
Ladies and gentlemen,
Dukes and Duchesses,
Barons and Baronesses,
Marquis and, you know,
the female version of those,
may I share a moment
of history with you.
Princess, would you join me up here?
Tonight, we celebrate
our love for the princess.
I, for one, can think of no better way
to celebrate the love I have
for this woman than this.
(squawks)
Oh, Eugene!
Wait. Did you drop something?
No.
Rapunzel, from the moment
I first met you
and you knocked me out
with that frying pan,
I knew it was love.
You're my light, you're my best friend
and I want to be
your partner in all things.
I can't wait to laugh
with you and share with you.
I see us raising our children here,
and our children's children,
and celebrating banquets
of our own in this very hall
for many, many, many,
many years to come.
I want to ride our horses
out to the Corona wall together
each and every morning
until we're both very,
very old and gray.
I love you, Rapunzel,
and I want to spend the rest
of our lives here together.
Here? In this...
castle forever?
I mean, unless you want to rent,
but I hardly see how
we're going to top this.
Eugene: And I want to spend the
rest of my life with you here,
and it doesn't get any better
than this, this castle...
King Frederic: Princesses need
to be protected at all times.
Rapunzel? Rapunzel?
(sighs) I've... Wow!
I love you, Eugene, but...
but I can't!
Just not, not now.
Um, I need some air.
(guests gasp, murmur)
Oh, I feel horrible about Eugene.
I... I do love him,
and I wanna marry him someday...
but not like this!
Ugh! I need to get out and clear my head
without a fleet of guards tailing me.
Say no more.
(gasps) Whoa!
Where's the war?
Well, when your dad is
captain of the guards,
you tend to collect stuff.
(tings, thunks)
I have a feeling
this is going to be fun.
Pascal, I need you to stay here
and make sure no one knows I'm gone.
The princess's lady-in-waiting
made it expressly clear...
Lady in wait...
What? You mean Cassandra?
First off, calling Cassandra
a "lady" anything,
is being incredibly generous.
Secondly, come on, Stan.
It's me, your buddy, Eugene.
Eugene the fiend.
You know Rapunzel would want
to talk to me if you let me in.
Sorry, Eugene, orders are orders.
All right. Just doing your job.
I respect that.
You sure there's no way to let me in?
Rapunzel?
(squeaks)
There you are, um...
Look, Rapunzel, I am sorry.
I am sorry, I should never have
put you on the spot like that.
But I want you to know, I meant it.
I want to marry you, I love you.
It's okay, you're still upset,
I understand.
You're not ready to say it back yet.
Totally cool.
Oh man, that is a good pillow!
What is that, goose down?
Some kind of down?
Horse hair? Alpaca?
Sorry, look...
I know there's still a ton of
details we need to figure out...
and I may have jumped the gun a little.
It's just that...
growing up poor and alone...
I got used to having nothing.
But now with you,
I finally have something,
you know? We have something.
Something that is amazing.
And I guess tonight I was just
trying to keep it that way.
And I thought that's what
you wanted too,
but I guess I was wrong.
(squeaks)
Oh come on, say something.
Ooh!
Fantastic. I just poured
my heart out to a frog.
Okay, where did she go?
Pascal, you do realize that if
the king finds out she's gone,
we're all going to be
in big trouble right?
I'm aware it's not protocol, Pete,
I just happen to think it
highlights my mustache.
Hey, Stan, great look!
I mean it really brings out the stache!
All right, you got us all here.
What's this plan of yours?
Oh, it's not my plan, boys.
It's Lady Caine's plan.
Did he say Lady Caine?
See, 18 years ago the princess
was taken from Corona,
and it was because of her
the king unfairly cracked down
on all those he considered undesirable.
Us.
Yeah, so?
Gentleman, Lady Caine is promising
not only to make you all rich,
but is offering you the opportunity
to exact revenge on the king
and his precious little princess.
So, who's in?
Is that a secret passage?
It was before you announced it
to the whole castle.
Rapunzel?
Rapunzel, are you in there?
(clears throat)
Is who in there, Eugene?
Huh? Uh, no one.
This is just part of my nightly routine.
You know? Yeah, checking
the castle for intruders,
keeping an eye on Rapunzel,
like I promised.
- Mm-hmm.
- Hey, is anyone in there?
No? Good!
See?
- The system works, really well I think...
- Eugene...
Where is Rapunzel?
Uh, ah... in her room of course.
Good. I'd like to speak with her.
You can't!
I mean, you can, obviously...
you can do whatever you want.
You're the king!
A very large, intimidating, beardy,
yet clearly understanding, King.
It's just, she's still upset
and she said she needed time alone.
I was only trying to respect that.
But, like I said, you are the king,
the very sweet and non-hostile king.
Well, maybe she does need
some time to herself,
but when you see her please tell
her that I am looking for her.
Sir, about the whole proposal earlier.
That didn't go quite as I had hoped.
We'll discuss that later, son,
much later.
Right, we both have bigger fish to fry.
That was so fun!
I'd like to take this
opportunity to remind you that
we're supposed to be sneaking out.
Cass, I think you'll discover that
I can be pretty sneaky when I need to...
Nightly patrols.
We can get by them if we time it right.
Wait, how did you know they were coming?
I have eyes in the sky.
(owl hooting)
That is amazing.
You have your own owl.
What's his name?
Owl.
(clicks tongue)
Max!
Yeah, when he heard
I was sneaking you out of here
he insisted he come along.
And between you and me,
I think he's got something
for you know who.
Hmm, it'll be our secret.
(sighs)
Oh honey, stop beating yourself up.
Rapunzel just needs some space.
Nobody said dealing with
teenagers would be easy.
Teenager or not, Ariana,
she will be queen one day.
I have to prepare her for that.
(baby crying)
King Frederic: Guards, guards.
My child.
Rapunzel!
I just want to protect her.
♪ Seems like I've spent
my whole life hoping ♪
♪ Dreaming of things I've never tried ♪
♪ Tangled in knots, just
waiting for my time to shine ♪
♪ What if the doors began to open? ♪
♪ What if the knots became untied? ♪
♪ What if one day
nothing stood in my way ♪
♪ And the world was mine? ♪
♪ Would it feel this fine? ♪
♪ 'Cause I got the wind in my hair ♪
♪ And a gleam in my eyes ♪
♪ On an endless horizon ♪
♪ I got a smile on my face
and I'm walking on air ♪
♪ And everything life ought to be ♪
♪ It's all gonna happen
to me out there ♪
♪ And I'll find it, I swear ♪
♪ With the wind in my hair ♪
♪ So many roads I've yet to travel ♪
♪ So many friends I haven't met ♪
♪ So many new adventures
just around the bend ♪
♪ Plenty of mysteries to unravel ♪
♪ Tons of mistakes to not regret ♪
♪ So much to see, and to do, and to be ♪
♪ A whole life to spend ♪
♪ And it doesn't end ♪
♪ 'Cause I got the wind in my hair ♪
♪ And a song in my heart ♪
♪ And the fun's only starting ♪
♪ I got a skip in my step
and I haven't a care ♪
♪ And everything life ought to be ♪
♪ Well, I know that it's
waiting for me out there ♪
♪ And I'll find it, I swear ♪
♪ With the wind in my hair ♪
Just remember,
no one can ever know I took you
outside the walls of Corona.
Don't worry!
No one is going to find out.
(ground rumbling)
Whoa! Whoa, Max.
All right, this looks dangerous.
Can you...
can you stay here
and watch Fidela for me?
So, what did you want to show me?
Believe me, it's better
if you see it for yourself.
They're beautiful.
What are they?
Don't know. They just
kind of sprouted up here
about a year ago.
And watch this...
Uh, you might want to
stand back for this one.
(grunts)
Wow!
They're unbreakable.
Want to know the weirdest part?
This is where they found
the miracle flower
that saved your mom.
And me.
Wait! What is...
Get to the horses as fast as you can
and don't look back, Rapunzel.
Don't stop, Rapunzel. Keep going!
Um, Cassandra!
Keep moving, Rapunzel. We need to get...
Whoa! What?
What happened?
I have no idea,
but we'll have to deal with it later.
Let's go!
(grunts)
Help!
Cassandra! My hair!
Whoa!
Ahh!
Cassandra!
Whoa!
See? I told you I'd get you in and out
without anyone knowing.
Piece of cake.
Piece of cake?
Uh, did you see the 70 feet of
"my father's going to kill me,"
growing from my head?
One problem at a time please.
We've got a problem.
Because of the coronation,
they've doubled security
at the gates today.
And there's no other way in?
Sure, if you want to walk in the
front door in broad daylight.
Hmm, maybe we don't need the front door.
(snorts)
I told him it wasn't protocol, sir.
(grunts)
Okay, quick, hand me the scissors.
So what do we wanna do here?
Maybe a bob? How about some layers?
Just cut it!
Uh-oh.
Uh-oh? Why uh-oh?
There shouldn't be any uh-ohs.
Uh-oh.
Was your hair always this strong?
What? No!
Try again.
(grunts)
We're gonna need a plan B.
Cover your eyes.
Ha!
Forget it.
It's just like those stupid
rocks. It's unbreakable.
We can't forget it!
Today is my coronation.
(knock on door)
Hey, sunshine, are you in there?
You can't let Eugene see you.
What? Why?
He can't know anything about last night.
I told you, Rapunzel.
If it gets out that I took you
outside Corona, I'm done for.
But I trust Eugene.
Well, I don't.
My dad will have me
taken off princess detail.
We'll never see each other again.
Eugene: Oh come on, we've been
looking for you all night.
Hey, are you okay in there?
I can hear you, you know?
(screams) Rapunzel!
Rapunzel?
Stand back!
Are you ok... Holy hair!
(laughs)
Surprise!
Whoa! Ooh, mama! Ha!
Okay! Okay.
This is new, I mean, no! Not new.
Right? Because we've
seen this, obviously.
That whole magic thing
is involved again.
It was magic right? Actually, you
know what? You don't need to tell me.
I'm just going to go ahead and say
your hair magically grew back.
I'm not going to ask how. Obviously
you don't want to tell me
or else you wouldn't have
to tried to hide it from me.
So, I won't ask how it grew back,
but tell me please,
how did it grow back?
Don't answer that. The important
thing is you're okay.
You're okay, right? Because as long as
you're okay, I don't care what happened.
But I mean, I care, obviously I care,
but I'm sure there is
a reasonable explanation.
Where is the war?
That you'll share when you're ready.
Thank you for understanding.
Oh, come one, really?
I thought we trusted
each other, Rapunzel.
We do! I do, it's just...
Fine, fine, fine. You know what?
I can't make you tell me what happened,
but obviously you're keeping
something from me.
But whatever it is,
I just want you to know
you should never feel like you
have to hide anything from me.
You don't hide things
from the people you love.
Ever.
Queen Arianna: Rapunzel, honey.
Hide your hair, woman!
You gotta hid your hair.
Rapunzel?
May I come in, sweetheart?
You can't! I'm...
brushing my teeth!
Queen Arianna: Oh, good.
But I can still come in, can't I?
Believe me Mom, you do not want to.
Morning breath.
Wouldn't wanna expose you to that.
That's ah, very thoughtful of you.
Um, Dad and I want you to join
us on the terrace for breakfast.
Um, I don't know.
There's a lot of stuff
I have to do to get ready.
Queen Arianna: Rapunzel, well,
your father has something very
important to share with you.
He's... he's been waiting all night.
Yeah, sure, um...
I will meet you there in a minute?
The coronation is in two hours!
How am I suppose to cut this hair?
I might have an idea.
So, Rapunzel, ready for the big day?
You bet! Already
into the princess spirit.
The bigger the wig,
the better the princess, right?
So Dad, Mom said you wanted to talk.
Yes... Rapunzel, last night,
your mother and I had a discussion.
(sighs)
I know that I'm not
always able to separate
the man from the king
and separating the father from the king
has proven even more difficult.
(sighs)
Sweetheart, I know this
new life is hard to get used to,
and I'm sure that sometimes you wish
I would get out of your hair.
(coughs)
Ooh, sorry.
It's a little, um, dry out here.
Anyone else dry?
Rapunzel,
you are going to be queen someday.
A great queen with a
magnificent kingdom.
But you know better than anyone else
what a dangerous and evil place
the world can be.
And the barrier keeping
us safe from that
is sometimes more fragile
than it appears.
When that evil rears its ugly head
it is my job to protect Corona from it.
And one day, that will be
your responsibility.
And I must teach you how to carry it.
But that is many, many years away.
Until that burden is imposed on you,
I'm asking that you trust me
that I know how to
keep danger as far away
from you and this kingdom
as is humanly possible.
Do you understand?
It was until last night that I realized
that my methods may have at times seemed
strict or unfair or...
Does this mean I can have
more time to myself
without having half the royal
guard over my shoulder?
Well, this means I'm willing
to reconsider those methods.
But I make no promises.
I can work with that.
(sniffs)
Well, I should go.
I have a lot of princessing up to do.
(chuckles)
You're right, Arianna.
Teenagers are a whole new frontier.
How are ya?
(whistling "Ode to Joy")
Oh, come on!
What is going on with Rapunzel?
I mean, is it something I did?
Probably.
And since when did she
start keeping secrets from me?
Hey, Fitzherbert, I need to get
this done before the coronation,
so do you mind throwing your
pity party someplace else?
Look, Cassandra,
I know you don't like me for Rapunzel...
Oh, that's not true.
I don't like you for anyone.
I just want what's best for her.
You don't say!
Of course! I want her to feel safe.
I want her to be taken care of
and I want her to be happy here.
Funny, you seem to have
a pretty good handle
on the things you want.
Oh, don't you start.
(knock on door)
Hi, honey.
Oh, hi Mom.
You left so quickly after breakfast I...
I didn't have a chance
to give this to you.
I know it's a little early
for a coronation gift but...
I thought you might like to see it now.
18th of July...
We embarked on a safari to the most
remote plains of the third continent.
21st of May...
Had to take shelter in a hidden cave
to escape the fury of a violent storm.
12th of April...
Helped villagers rebuild
their war torn homes.
Mom, is this yours?
Did you actually do all this?
Rapunzel,
before I met your father,
I was so much like you.
I had no idea what I was
supposed to do in this world.
So I went out and found my own way.
You're father is right about one thing,
You will be queen someday,
but only you get to decide
what kind of queen you'll be.
And no one can tell you the
best way to make that decision.
But how can I if...
Wait...
- are you suggesting that I should...
- Honey...
find a way to fill those pages.
I only ask that you be safe,
be smart, and above all...
be true to yourself.
Plus est en vous?
Plus est en vous.
It means, "There is more in you."
This would have been so much easier
with the other girls helping,
but they're such gossips,
half the kingdom would know
about your hair by now.
Are you sure you can't see it?
Positive. Are you sure
you can pull this off?
I have to, Cassandra.
Just be careful you don't trip on this.
It's not the dress I'm worried about.
How do people walk in these things?
Whoa! (sighs)
Just relax.
This is going to be fine.
I can't wait any longer.
This better work, Pocket.
Don't you worry, boys.
Lady Caine will not disappoint.
Okay.
Wow.
Whoa! (chuckles)
Whoa!
Oh, whoa!
How embarrassing for her.
This is going to take forever.
Hello? Can anyone help me?
Silly me, I must've taken
a wrong turn somewhere.
I'll be glad to help you, madam.
Oh, you're too kind!
(moans)
Hey, Madam Poppycock?
The party's upstairs.
Meet Lady Caine.
You're a lot stronger than you look.
I'm a lot of things.
Let the show begin.
I'm gonna need you to step back
into that cell, pronto.
That there is a nice suit.
The wearer of this crown
is a shining example of the promise
that is Corona,
an ambassador of goodwill
to those visiting from afar,
and an inspiration
to those fortunate enough
to live within her borders.
But above all, the chief
responsibility of the crown
is to keep the people of Corona safe
from dangers, near and far.
And their are many.
This mandate is not to be taken
- lightly.
- Go find Max.
There will come a day when
the walls that surround Corona
are threatened by malfeasance. A day...
- Attention, please!
- Lady Caine?
(screaming)
Release my guests immediately.
What's the matter, Fred?
Am I ruining your
little girl's perfect day?
The duchess?
Oh honey, I am no duchess.
I don't understand.
Of course you wouldn't, Rapunzel.
But try to follow along.
This is all your fault.
What?
You see, after your
untimely disappearance,
Your father locked up every
criminal in the kingdom,
including a simple petty thief.
My father...
I saw him thrown into a cage
and hauled off like some animal,
never to be seen again.
So, I thought I'd come back
and return the favor.
Load 'em up, boys.
Your turn, Your Majesty.
Oh come now,
you didn't think we'd leave our
prized pig in the pen, did you?
Dad?
Rapunzel, stay back.
- But...
- No. There's nothing you can do.
As your father and your king,
I command you to stay put.
Don't be a hero, pretty boy.
Sorry, Dad...
I can't stay put.
Rapunzel!
That's my girl!
Let them go!
(chuckles) It's amazing what
you can hide under those wigs,
isn't it, Princess.
Come on, let's move out!
Ugh, now you're just making me angry.
Good, because I'm just getting started.
Get those people back here, now!
Rapunzel, your hair!
I know, we'll talk about it later.
Please get somewhere safe
and take care of Mom.
- Rapunzel!
- That's my cue...
Yeah!
Well, my last day on princess duty.
Might as well go down fighting.
Leave them alone.
So, you sure you can handle yourself?
Oh, I'll manage.
Get that door open, now!
Aw... cute.
Rapunzel!
Thanks, blondie.
Haha! Now this feels good.
Stay down!
You have no idea
who you are dealing with.
Believe me, I've dealt with much worse.
You think this is over?
Ha! I promise you,
I'll be back.
Oh... (tsking) Lady Caine.
It's impolite to leave
in the middle of a party.
You think you'd know that.
(cheers and applause)
Nice to see ya. Thanks for coming!
Nice suit, buddy.
Happy Coronation Day folks.
So I'm trying to understand this.
You snuck out last night
went beyond the walls of Corona,
where you touched a mysterious rock,
that somehow caused your hair to return?
Yes.
And you acted alone?
Look, I know you're angry,
but can't you see? I'm okay!
I'm more than okay, I...
Rapunzel...
There's something I need to tell you.
I love you.
The night you were taken,
a part of me died,
the best part of me.
For 18 long and agonizing years I swore
that if somehow,
someway, by some miracle
the fates decided to show mercy
and return you to me,
I would never let anything
happen to you again.
And now that this has returned,
the very reason you were snatched
away from me in the first place,
I'm afraid I'm left
with no choice, sweetheart.
As of tonight,
I'm forced to exercise
my martial right as king
to forbid you from leaving the walls
of this kingdom without my consent.
- Father!
- And know this...
This is the last we will
speak of mystical rocks
or magic of any kind to anyone.
Is that understood?
There is so much more
to me than you think.
(knock on door)
Come in.
I believe somebody ordered room service?
Eugene, how did you know?
Ah, I had a feeling.
Look, I just wanted
to clear some stuff up.
I haven't had a chance to apologize for
putting you on the spot
with that proposal.
Well looking back,
storming out of the room
probably wasn't the best reaction.
So I'm sorry.
No, don't apologize.
Look I'll admit, I don't quite
understand why you said "no."
But I promise to do
everything I can until I do.
Thanks, Eugene.
In the mean time,
we'll stay right here
and take things slowly.
I miss this.
Hey, promise me one more thing.
Anything.
That you'll be patient with me.
Absolutely.
Good night, Rapunzel.
Good night, Eugene.
♪ Back to life after
happily ever after ♪
♪ Stuck inside once again
and I'm gazing out ♪
♪ True I'm in here
with those I hold dear ♪
♪ Surrounded by their love ♪
♪ And for some,
that's more than enough ♪
♪ No doubt ♪
♪ But I got the wind in my hair ♪
♪ And a fire within ♪
♪ 'Cause there's something beginning ♪
♪ I got a mystery to solve ♪
♪ And excitement to spare ♪
♪ That beautiful breeze
blowing through ♪
♪ I'm ready to follow it
who knows where ♪
♪ And I'll get there, I swear ♪
♪ With the wind in my hair ♪
Synced & corrected by kinglouisxx
www.addic7ed.com
♪ But I got the wind in my hair ♪
♪ And a fire within ♪
♪ 'Cause there's something beginning ♪
♪ I got a mystery to solve ♪
♪ And excitement to spare ♪
♪ That beautiful breeze
blowing through ♪
♪ I'm ready to follow it
who knows where ♪
♪ And I'll get there, I swear ♪
♪ With the wind in my hair ♪